Daniel C. McKinney papers, 1929-1948
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Daniel C. McKinney papers, 1929-1948
AZ 014
McKinney, Daniel C., 1898-1969
Correspondence, financial papers, reports, and related materials dealing with activities in the Arizona Cattle Growers' Association, the Arizona Livestock Sanitary Board, various farm credit associations, the livestock interests of the Hearst Enterprises, and the California Cattlemen's Association. Included is political material concerning Osborn's 1940 campaign, and McKinney's own campaign in 1942.
.4 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Cattle rancher; President, Arizona Cattle Growers' Association, 1932, Member, Arizona Livestock Sanitary Board, 1931-1932, worked with various credit banks and the Hearst Corporation analyzing livestock and ranching operations. Managed primary campaign for Sidney P. Osborn, Democratic nominee for Governor of Arizona, 1940. McKinney was a 1942 candidate for the Democratic nomination for Governor of Arizona.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Business and Association Correspondence, 1929-1939
Series II: Hearst Enterprises Papers, 1935-1938
Series III: Political Campaign Materials, 1940- 1948
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, financial papers, reports, and related materials dealing with activities in the Arizona Cattle Growers' Association, the Arizona Livestock Sanitary Board, various farm credit associations, the livestock interests of the Hearst Enterprises, and the California Cattlemen's Association. Included is political material concerning Osborn's 1940 campaign, and McKinney's own campaign in 1942.
Access Terms
Osborn, Sidney Preston, 1884-1948
Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951
Arizona -- Livestock Board
Arizona Cattle Growers' Association
California Cattlemen's Association
Hearst Sunical Land and Packing Corporation
Babicora Development Company
Democratic Party (Ariz.)
Cattle trade -- Arizona
Cattle trade -- California
Cattle trade -- Mexico
Cattle -- Economic Aspects -- Arizona
Arizona -- Politics and government -- 20th century
Correspondence
Speeches
Container List
- Series I: Business and Association Correspondence, 1929-1939
  - Arizona Cattle Grower's Association. 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Livestock Sanitary Board. 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Various credit organizations, personal business, etc. 1931-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Hearst Enterprises, 1935-1938
  - Correspondence, reports, memos. 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Babicora Development Co., Mexico--miscellaneous financial papers, map, etc. 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hearst Sunical Land and Packing Corporation, miscellaneous financial papers. 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series III: Political Campaign Materials, 1940-1948
  - "Osborn for Governor," political campaign (includes correspondence, clippings, speeches). 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "McKinney for Governor," political campaign (includes correspondence, clippings, speeches, campaign literature). 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - California Cattlemen's Association (correspondence, publications, etc.). 1942-1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)